Look at many of the items around your home and some will probably have been imported from abroad by ship.
看看你家里的许多物品，有些可能是通过船从国外进口的。
Moving goods around the world by sea is the easiest and most cost-effective way to do it.
通过海路在全球运输货物是最容易、成本效益最高的方式。
But what has made it more practical is the invention of the shipping container.
但使其更加切实可行的是航运集装箱的发明。
They're not the most amazing thing to look at, but because of their design, and especially their universal size, it means they can be loaded and unloaded on to huge vessels at any port that is big enough to accommodate them.
它们看起来并不是最令人惊叹的东西，但由于它们的设计，特别是它们通用的尺寸，这意味着它们可以在任何足够大的港口被装卸到巨大的船只上。
The standardisation of these simple metal containers in the 1950s and 60s marked a turning point in world trade, driving down costs and ultimately leading to globalisation.
这些简易金属集装箱在20世纪50年代和60年代的标准化标志着世界贸易的一个转折点，降低了成本，并最终导致了全球化。
Inside these versatile metal boxes could be anything from nappies to cars, and they are transported on container ships that ply our seas and oceans.
在这些多功能金属箱子里，可以是任何东西，从尿布到汽车，它们由定期航行在我们海洋上的集装箱船运输。
They have been described as 'the monsters of the seas' because of their huge size.
由于它们巨大的尺寸，它们被称为"海洋怪物"。
The very biggest are almost half a kilometre long and are piled high with more than 20,000, 20-foot-long boxes.
最大的那些几乎有半公里长，高高堆叠着超过20,000个20英尺长的箱子。
In fact, the world's largest, The Port of Rotterdam, has a capacity of 24,346 TEU – an exact unit of measurement used to determine cargo capacity for container ships and terminals.
事实上，世界上最大的集装箱船，鹿特丹号，其运力为24,346个标准箱（twenty-foot equivalent unit）——这是一个用于确定集装箱船和码头货物容量的精确计量单位。
With around 5,500 container ships globally, it's incredible to think about the amount of goods being moved around the world.
全球大约有5,500艘集装箱船，想到在全球范围内运输的货物数量，真是令人难以置信。
However, because we now rely so much on these global shipments of goods, there can be problems when things go wrong.
然而，由于我们现在如此依赖这些全球货物运输，一旦出现问题，就可能产生麻烦。
In 2021, the Ever Given, loaded with 18,000 containers, got stuck in the Suez Canal – blocking an important trade route.
2021年，装载着18,000个集装箱的"长赐"轮在苏伊士运河搁浅——堵塞了一条重要的贸易路线。
Countless businesses were affected by the delay in receiving their goods.
无数企业因收货延迟而受到影响。
One shipping company, Maersk, said the "ripple effects on global capacity and equipment" were significant.
航运公司马士基表示，这对"全球运力和设备的连锁反应"是意义重大的。
Despite the occasional problems, our demand for goods is increasing, and so the shipping container is here to stay.
尽管偶尔出现问题，但我们对商品的需求正在增加，因此集装箱将继续存在。
George Griffiths from S&P Global Platts told the BBC: "We're seeing a lot more of the ultra-large container ships being built… the proportion of new ships that are moving over 14,000 containers is staggering."
来自标普全球普氏能源资讯的乔治·格里菲斯告诉BBC："我们知道越来越多的超大型集装箱船在建……新建船舶中运力超过14,000个集装箱的比例是惊人的。"
Each container can have a lifespan of up to 25 years.
每个集装箱的使用寿命可达25年。
And even when the effects of wind, waves and loading takes its toll, some find a new lease of life as land-based storage units or even used as houses and hotels!
即使当风、海浪和装载的影响造成损害后，一些集装箱也会作为陆基存储单元，甚至被用作房屋和酒店而获得新生！